For two months he's been lying here in a coma helpless.
What are his chances, Doctor?
Not good. We're still trying to locate his family.
Seeing him like this, it just makes me realize.
I love you, Deondra.
And cut! Crouch!
Oh! Ernie! Ernie!
What'd you think?
I laughed, I cried.
You're on a five.
Okay, thanks. Mike!
Kate! Kate! You're wonderful!
Oh, thank you!
You know, I'm really getting into this coma stuff, and I think people are starting
to notice. Nice coma today, Siever.
Oh, thank you, Mr.
Chakin. That means a lot coming from you.
Lynette, Castiel Fleckman, head writer.
It is a pleasure.
Oh, I see your name on the credits every week.
Wow! Sweetheart, you want to get me a cup of coffee and rip the top off a muffin?
Do I want to what?
Uh, s -excuse me.
Uh, honey, I think he wants to talk to me alone.
Just -just this once.
We've been so impressed with your performance.
You are Strom Waverly.
I mean, the way you've explored textures, finding the internal harmonics.
Yeah, right. Ditto.
I hope for your sake you can keep a secret.
Yeah. Yeah, what's this?
The episode America's been waiting for?
Next Thursday, we reveal the name of the murderer.
You're kidding. But only my character knows.
You mean I wake up, I say the name of the murderer?
Put a sock in it, Brainiac!
This is just the beginning, Strom.
You'll be the flame that drives the passion burning at the heart of big city
secrets. Besides, wardrobe says you look great without a shirt.
Really? I, uh, I actually catch cold easily.
I love this kid.
Does that mean I get a raise?
I don't love anybody that much.
Remember, Strom, you must store the murderer's name in the strong box of your heart.
In other words, below the secret, I drop a grenade in your shorts.
Kate, Kate, Kate, are you ready for the most exciting news in your entire life?
What is it?
I can't tell you.
Absolutely nobody's supposed to know.
Mr. Seaver, Glenn just told me the news.
And he sent you over to congratulate me?
Now he wants his coffee in his muffin tub.
Honey, I can't believe you actually got him a cup of coffee.
I can't believe I actually spit in it.
Show me that smile, oh, show me that smile.
Don't waste another minute on your crying.
We're going near, near, north and near The best is ready to begin Oh, oh As long as
we got each other We got the world spinning right in our hands But you and me, we
gotta be The luckiest dreamers who never quit dreaming As long as we keep on giving
We can take anything that comes our way.
Baby rain or shine, all the time.
We got each other sharing the laughter and love.
Sharing the laughter and love.
A line? You have an actual line?
Yes, with syllables and everything.
Jason, syllables. Can I have your autograph to take to school?
Sure, sweetheart. Can you sign it Jason Priestley?
Wait a minute, you've been on the show for six months and you haven't had a line?
But I couldn't talk.
I was in an accident and practically brain dead.
Well, it doesn't stop Geraldo Rivera.
So, uh, who's the murderer?
What makes you so sure I know?
Come on, Strom Waverly is the only one who knows.
Monica found out, but she was killed by Dakota's evil twin at Cruise Banister
Chateau. What, don't you guys ever watch TV?
Don't you ever go to school?
Yes, that's right.
I'm home again for dinner.
My roommate, Brianne, is hosting a soap opera fan club meeting.
Can you believe they actually have clubs devoted to discussing that garbage?
Can anybody join?
Anybody with half a brain.
All right. Hey, more good news to celebrate.
That was the Child Welfare Bureau.
They may have found a home for Luke.
Whoa. That was fast.
Hmm. You think they could take Carol, too?
So, honey, who are they?
Dr. and Mrs.
Kimball. They'll be here for dinner Wednesday night.
But, Daddy, can't Luke stay with us forever?
Ah, who'd want that?
Besides, you got a full house ready.
And if I didn't have a place of my own, how would you come visit me, huh?
Huh? Oh, Carol, good.
You're not busy.
Hey, what are you doing?
Okay, Carol, Carol.
I need you to watch me do my line and tell me what you think.
Mike, leave me alone.
If I make enough money, I'll move out.
I'm all ears.
Just make it fast.
Okay, okay. Uh, ooh, let me give you some background.
Now, in 1974, Taylor Pomerance, the patriarch of Green Valley, disinherited his
three sons, Frisco, Corrigan, and Murray.
Do any of those things make you feel better?
How many of them know your line?
My line, okay.
Now, I'm in a hospital room.
The stillness punctuated only by the sound of the monitor.
Ka -bing, ka -bing.
Mike! The line.
Right, right. Whoa!
Wait! Ah! What kind of a line is that?
No, no, that's not my line.
I'm just getting prepared.
Mike! I'm sorry.
Cruz Banister. Well?
Well what? You lay there and belched.
No, no, no, no, no, Carol.
That was the name of the murderer.
But you're right, I can do much better than that.
Cruz Banister! Well?
They pay you for this?
A speck of protoplasm could do better.
Okay, you're right, you're right.
What was I thinking?
He's still on the respirator.
Cruz vanister. C -C -Cruz vanister.
Howdy, stranger. Oh, shut up.
Brianne, let me appeal to you as a human being.
Cool. You see, I'm falling behind in my studies, and I can't study at home because
my brother keeps rehearsing his stupid soap opera line, and I can't study here
because... because you're an insensitive boob.
And my academic performance is suffering.
I am suffering.
And all I ask of you is a little human understanding.
Carol, you have never mentioned this before.
Your brother is on a soap opera?
Which one? Who does he play?
I don't know.
I don't care.
He just lies there and breathes.
Ah! My roomie's brother is Strom Waverly III.
Whose brother? Carol, my roommate.
I didn't know you had a roommate.
What? Girls, Carol Sieber, sister of Strong Waverly the Third.
No! I can't believe we've never met before.
I'm Jennifer, and this is Tiffany and Megan and Courtney and...
Are you gonna come to the big party on Friday?
Well, I wasn't invited.
You weren't? Well, the party's in this room.
Promise me you'll come.
Wait a minute.
I once knew a guy who said he played the Wookie in Star Wars.
Turned out he just had a low hairline.
How do we know your brother really is Strom Waverly?
Yeah. Prove it.
Well, if he weren't on the show, how would I know the name of the murderer is...
Cruz Banister. Cruz Banister?
Cruz Banister? The murderer is Cruz Banister?
That's it? Harold, do you think you could take us to see the show?
Hey, I'm his acting coach.
All right. There, I almost got it.
How'd you learn so much about fixing dolls?
Oh, I was a surgeon at a doll hospital.
You were not.
Oh, yeah? When Chatty Cathy lost her voice, who do you think got her talking again?
When Betsy Wetsey dried up like the Sahara,
who do you think opened up the floodgates?
And when my little pony got the trots, who do you think got her back on track?
Let's see. Well, it's as good as new.
Thanks, Luke. When I'm all grown up, you better wash out.
Hey, Luke. What are you doing dressed up in Ben's weenie suit?
I want to make a good impression on the Kimbles.
So you're dressing like Ben?
Ellen, if these people don't like you the way you are, then the heck with them.
Go upstairs, throw on some jeans.
Mike! What a pleasant surprise.
I didn't hear you come in.
You had some phone messages.
Yeah? What'd you do, burn them?
Ha! There's that urbane wit of yours.
You had. Two publicists, an agent, and a writer from a soap opera magazine.
Would you like me to call them back for you?
Carol, did they do some kind of brain experiment on your couch?
Mike, it just so happens that I'm your sister and I love you very much, and can I
bring everyone from my dorm to see your show, please?
Oh, I get it.
You need me to help you make some friends in your dorm.
Mike, don't make this any harder than it is.
Oh, well, Carol, wasn't it you who just a few days ago said that I had less talent
than, uh... What was that again?
A speck of protoplasm.
Right. Oh, gee, I don't know.
We're kind of thin -skinned.
All right, then.
You're handsome. You're talented.
And? And you are major beefcake.
And? And I think I'm gonna throw up.
That's what I wanted to hear.
Okay, sure, bring him by and I'll see what I can do.
Creep jerk. Whoa, whoa, what was that?
I say keep up the good work.
That must be the Kimbals.
You seen Luke?
Yeah, yeah, he's upstairs trying to look less like Ben.
Good thinking. Hello.
Doctor and Mrs.
Seaver? Shelly and Jim Kimball.
Hello. Hi, I'm Jason, this is Maggie.
That's our son Mike, and Luke will be down in just a minute.
Please come in.
Sit. Thank you.
So, tell us about yourselves.
Well, I'm a veterinarian.
I'm a housewife, and in my spare time, I record books for the blind.
Our apartment isn't huge, but Luke will have his own bedroom and bathroom.
We're in an excellent school district.
And on weekends, we go up to my brother's fishing cabin in the Adirondacks.
Nice. Dad, Dad, you mind if I just ask a question?
No, go ahead, Mike.
So, Dr. Kimball, what's in this for you?
Hi. Dr. Kimball, I'm very sorry.
Come on. We don't know anything about these people.
Anybody can claim to be a veterinarian.
I am a veterinarian.
Oh, well, then what would you do, hypothetically speaking, if a cat came limping
into this limping?
Doctor, if you excuse our son, he's very protective of Luke.
By the way, what would you do?
Jason. I'm sorry.
I'm just... It's all right.
We understand. Yeah, please, ask us anything.
Certainly, Dr. Kimball.
if that's your real name.
Mike. Bottom line, why do you want Luke?
Well, Shelley and I were both orphans ourselves.
We know what it's like to be unwanted and unloved.
We'd like to be able to help Luke out, give him the family we never had.
Oh, that's very touching.
How long did you rehearse that one?
Oh, good night.
It was really nice meeting you, Luke.
Ah, Dr. Kimball, I'm sorry if I was a little tough on you earlier, but you came
through with flying colors.
Well, I'm glad to hear it, Mike.
And I'll get that financial statement over to you right away.
Thank you. Why don't I show you to your car?
Good night. Good night.
Nice to meet you.
Bye -bye. What a wonderful couple.
Well, Luke, do you like them?
Oh, it's not to like.
Horseback riding, season Mets tickets, ski trips.
Yeah, and who knew that in a pinch you could fix a cat leg with a popsicle stick?
Huh? Well? Luke didn't love you.
They don't even want to wait till next week.
They want to come back and pick you up Friday night.
Oh, wow. That's great.
Oh, man, did I tell you we'd find you a good home or what?
Yeah, you sure did.
Oh, Luke. Oh, that's great.
Wow, this dressing room's huge!
Oh, wow. Kate, look at this.
My sofa. My waste paper basket.
And look at this.
My chair with my name on it.
Mark Siever? Oh, I can't have everything.
Glenn. Glenn, oh, hey, you remember my girl?
Can it. Bad news.
Strom, Strom, Strom, we've rewritten your whole scene.
You're kidding. Do I still wake up?
Of course, but you don't say Cruz Banister anymore.
Now you say Brooke Sunderfield.
He's the murderer?
She. Wow. This is a curveball.
Uh, Brooke Sunderfield.
Is that okay?
Is this kid a trooper or what?
Blow it, I yank out your nose hair.
Uh, why did you change the name of the murderer?
Oh, some serpent in our midst gave the name Cruz Banister to the Columbia University
paper. The more I think about it, the more I'd like to pop the weasel who did it.
Oh, kids today.
Scrum, better get into wardrobe.
Roll tape in five minutes.
Okay, okay, right.
You need anything, you let me know.
Okay, I can't think of a thing.
Oh, I can.
This may seem petty, but Ernie put Mark on the chair and...
Say no more.
Ernie's history, he's fired.
No, no, no, no, no.
Just maybe I'll change the name on the chair, but don't fire anybody.
Well, okay. Well?
Oh, sorry -looking buns.
Hello, Strom Waverly the Third.
Yeah, hello, is Mike Siever there?
Yeah, Luke, hey, it's me, Mike.
I was just getting into character.
What's up? Look, you've been straight with me.
I felt I owed you a goodbye.
A goodbye? Hey, listen, pal, you're just moving across town.
I'm leaving town.
Luke, where are you going?
I'll spend the winter in Florida.
Don't worry, I'll be fine.
All buses will be boarding from the upper contours.
Luke, don't do this!
I'll look you up someday.
Luke! Oh! What's wrong?
Kate, call the bus station.
Find out the next bus that leaves for anywhere in Florida.
Mike, I know you're nervous about today, but running away isn't the answer.
No, no, Kate.
I'm not running.
Luke is. Knock, knock, knock.
Five minutes, Mr.
Siever. Ah, get Glen and Lynette.
I got a problem.
Gwen, my nursing kid's got a problem!
Strong, why aren't you in wardrobe?
Look, is there any way that we can put this off till tomorrow?
Impossible. Tomorrow you'll lead the SWAT team to the murderer's lair with your
shirt off. Well, maybe we could just delay it for an hour or two.
Entertainment Tonight is here for crying out loud.
Be a man!
Look, there's this boy that's been living with our family and he's about to run back
on the streets and I'm the only one who can stop him.
Entertainment Tonight!
There's a bus for Fort Lauderdale in 20 minutes.
Okay, okay, so I can be back as soon as I...
So this boy's been in your home, and now at the moment of truth your heart goes out
to him. It's wonderful.
So can I go?
No! But that storyline screams daytime Emmy.
Can't you just let him go?
Is she anybody?
No. This scene suits in five minutes with you in that bed.
Strom, I have designed whole storylines around you.
This is a once in a lifetime opportunity.
I know, I understand.
Look, I have an idea.
What about, uh, If we put a dummy in the bed today, and tomorrow I'll come back and
do the shirtless swat thing.
How about this?
No more Strom, you're fired!
Are you serious?
It's so simple.
Stay not fired.
Leave fired. History.
Out of here.
Deep sixed. I gotta go.
Oh? Well, there's the door.
You're fired! No, no, no, no, no.
You don't understand.
People cry and throw themselves at my feet and beg me to hire them back when they're
fired. And you're fired!
I heard you.
Listen, I lost my head.
You're not fired.
We'll work something out.
Thanks. And now that you're working for me again, you're fired!
Finita! End of the line!
Bing, bang, boom, you're out!
Something's wrong. I'm not enjoying this.
Forget him. He's obviously not strong.
Of course not.
Because he's fired!
He doesn't even exist.
In fact, I don't even know who I'm talking to.
Nobody's there. I'm talking to air.
Air. Air. Look, Kate, I gotta find my jacket.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Don't worry about me.
Just go. I'm proud of you, Mark Siever.
Can I help you?
Yes. I'm looking for Mike Siever.
Never heard of him.
Well, he's on this show.
I should know.
I'm his sister.
Excuse me, Toots.
I've only been with this show since it was created, you know?
You don't believe me?
Go ask the producer there.
You're fired! Fire, fire, fire!
You understand? Hi.
I'm looking for Mike Siever.
Mike Siever? There is no Mike Siever.
where there never was a Mike Siever.
There's just air.
Air. Air. I smell a wookie.
Wait, wait, I can prove it.
The murderer's name is on page 14.
Brooks Underfield? I knew Cruz couldn't have done it.
Wait! This is Mike.
Look, this is my brother.
What are you kids doing here?
We are not kids.
We are students from Columbia University.
Ah! Security! Excuse me.
Excuse me. It's busy.
Luke? Mike? Hey.
What are you doing in here?
You're supposed to be in a coma.
Come on. Let's get out of here.
I can't. I'll lose my free seat.
You're going to ride all the way to Florida in a restroom?
He's hanging onto the back with a skateboard.
Come on. Come on.
Let's go. Just let me go.
Like I'm going to let you wander the streets while I lead the SWAT team to the
killer with my shirt off.
Fort Lauderdale Express.
Get comfortable or get off.
Look, what was wrong with the Kimbles?
Hey, I don't trust a man who uses a popsicle stick to fix a cat.
I'm serious. What was wrong with the chemicals?
Nothing. I'm just tired of getting used to people and having them ditch me.
Ditch you? Yeah.
My dad split when I was two.
My mom died and...
You guys are...
Us? Luke, look how great you fit in with us.
I mean, after only a month, you were part of our family.
Not quite. Driver, stop this bus.
Uh, blow it out of here.
Jason, Jason, I heard a noise downstairs.
Maybe Luke's back.
Are you awake?
Mm -hmm. Mm -hmm.
Mom, Dad, look, I'm sorry it's so late, but I've made a decision.
I don't want Luke going to the Kimbells.
I want Luke to stay right here, and I will take full responsibility for him.
Mike. Mom, you said it yourself.
Luke fits in around here.
Well, that's true.
And that's because he loves us, and we love him.
And that's the bottom line.
Well, I can't say I haven't had the same thought from time to time, but Jason.
Mm -hmm. That makes it unanimous, Tim.
Thanks, Mom. We'll work it out in the morning.
Okay. Thanks, Dad.
Mike, your father and I are proud of you.
Mm -hmm. Good night.
Good night. Oh, Jason.
Isn't this wonderful?
Jason. Jason, wake up.
What's going on?
What is it?
What? Jason, what's going on?
We just had another child.
I'm going to be a little bit of a I'm going to be a little bit of a
I'm going to be a little bit of a I'm going to be a little bit of a I'm going to go
to bed. I'm going to go to bed.
I'm going to go to bed.